pfaw.org 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy | People For the American Way

People for the American Way is committed to protecting the privacy and security of visitors to our websites. Outlined below is our online privacy policy for information collected through this website and email lists. If you have any questions about these policies, we encourage you to talk to us either by:

  * emailing us at [pfaw@pfaw.org](mailto:pfaw@pfaw.org), or
  * contacting our Membership Department at 1.800.326.7329.

## Browser information collected on our website

As with any website operator, PFAW analyzes our website logs to constantly improve the value of our website. We use an external service to provide real-time reporting to us and our authorized agents, including vendors of browser accesses to our site, including page views, unique views, unique visitors, repeat visitors, frequency of visits, and peak-volume traffic periods. We do not use this service to gather, request, record, require, collect, or track any Internet users’ personally identifying information.

We use cookies on our site to customize the experience of our visitors and to support some necessary functions. We also use cookies to better understand how our visitors use our site. In some instances, we will allow third parties to place cookies on our site, but only under the conditions outlined under “Resale or disclosure of information to third parties.” We do not look at cookies on your machine for other sites.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. For more information on how to modify your browser settings to block or filter cookies, see [www.cookiecentral.com/faq/](http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq/). However, note that if you reject some or all cookies, your experience at our sites and on other sites throughout the World Wide Web may not be complete. In addition, if you do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of personalized content delivery offered by other Internet sites or us.

## Voluntarily submitted data

You may be invited to share personally identifying information on online donation forms and petitions, over the phone, by mail, and through email list sign-up forms. We may use this information to process your donations, contact you about PFAW activities or news, display your information in the case of a petition delivery, and deliver content to you on platforms such as social media, other websites, and search results pages.

## Privacy of our email lists

PFAW maintains several email lists to keep PFAW members and policy makers informed about breaking events. We do not share or otherwise disclose your email addresses to other organizations except where you authorize it (for example, in petitions to elected officials).  Only PFAW staff and our authorized agents have access to personally identifiable information provided by visitors to our site.

From time to time, we may send you information from other like-minded organizations whose products or services we think subscribers might find interesting, but we do not exchange, trade, rent, or give email lists to these parties. The external organization will only learn information that you choose to disclose at the time of the communication.

## Privacy of our donor lists

PFAW collects information including name, email address, and mailing address from donors online and through mail and phone calls. Names and mailing addresses may be shared with other like-minded organizations that we think our members may be interested in hearing from in the interest of cutting costs and reaching more supporters about our activities. If you do not want us to share your name or mailing address with other like-minded organizations, please call 1.800.326.7329 and ask to speak with a Member Services representative or email us directly at [pfaw@pfaw.org](mailto:pfaw@pfaw.org). We comply with federal, state, and local laws regarding disclosure of nonprofit and campaign donations.

## Resale or disclosure of information to third parties

In addition, we work with a variety of vendors who help us process data and facilitate operations of our website and mailings. When we share information through these activities, your data is kept confidential. In some instances, we may allow the vendor to use your data for other purposes such as improvement of their products, modeling and analytics, or benchmarking for other clients. You will never be identifiable as an individual in the aggregated reports.

## Children’s privacy

Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulation establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly collect contact or personal information from children under 13. Our sites are not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we have designed our sites to block our knowing acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age related information is requested.

It is possible that by fraud or deception by others we may receive information given to us or pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent or otherwise delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by e-mailing us at [webmaster@pfaw.org](mailto:webmaster@pfaw.org).

## Security

We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving financial data from our site. In addition, we have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss or misuse of information that we have collected from you at our site.

## Updates to This Policy

We reserve the right to update the terms of this Policy at any given time.  We recommend that you continue to visit this page for such updates.
